<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Python | Moon Limb's Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://moonlimb.github.com/blog/categories/python/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://moonlimb.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-10-16T18:58:33-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://moonlimb.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Moon Limb]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[moonlimb@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Can I become a Software Engineer in 10 Weeks?]]></title>
    <link href="http://moonlimb.github.com/blog/2012/10/15/can-i-become-a-software-engineer-in-10-weeks/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-15T22:16:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://moonlimb.github.com/blog/2012/10/15/can-i-become-a-software-engineer-in-10-weeks</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My experiences as a student at Hackbright Academy began on October 1st, 2012. <a href="http://www.hackbrightacademy.com/">Hackbright Academy</a>, it is a 10-week intensive program that trains women with problem solving mindset but without the traditional computer science background to become software engineers and web developers. It is currently run by three amazing people: Christian, Charles and David (<a href="https://twitter.com/chriszf">@chriszf</a>, <a href="https://twitter.com/cruhland">@cruhland</a>, and <a href="https://twitter.com/davjphillips">@davjphillips</a>, respectively).</p>

<p>I am one of the 16 women in the Hackbright's second batch. While everyone adds a unique color and character to our batch, all share a similiar curiosity for learning to program. I find the immersive coding environment to be conducive to learning and befitting such rigorous program, but impossible without the instructors such as Christian and Charles. They both have two invaluable qualities of a teacher: ability to explain complex things with clarity and patience, and genuine interest and responsibility with which they approach educating.</p>

<p>In college, I felt that whenever I got engrossed in a project or a subject, my engagement with other courses and assignments suffered. At the moment, I am truly happy to be able to focus on, theoretically, one learning objective: learning to code well in Python. In order to find out whether something is a right career path for you, my advice is to completely immerse yourself in it at the risk of failure. If I didn't all-in on programming, I would have never found out how much I enjoyed it; I would have easily given up when learning got diffcult, with excuses such as "I don't know how to think like a computer scientist." Now, I can't imagine my life without programming.</p>

<p>10 weeks won't cover everything I want to learn, especially not the entire 4-year curriculum traditional computer science majors undergo. In fact, there's only 8 more weeks left in the program (I have completed 20% of the program already!). With stacks of tools and terminologies to familiarize myself with, skills to build, and Hacker News articles to read, it is and will certainly be overwhelming at times. But I realize that quality learning will make me a better hands-on programmer than the quantity of information I can hash out.</p>

<p>This blog will trace my learning during Hackbright and beyond. It will focus on my codes, endeavours to debug and refactor them, and personal thoughts on both coding and non-coding alike. Through blogging, I hope to put my inspirations to a productive use, and chronicle my experiences as I transition from a thinker and an idealist to a builder and an engineer. Any comments or feedback are always welcome!</p>

<p>It's important to mention that <a href="http://natashatherobot.com/">Natasha's blog</a> was an inspiration for this blog. I find it inspiring that you can be a learner and a teacher at the same time, empowering other beginner coders by sharing learning experiences and resources. In my blog, I hope to do my best to use my fresh learner's perspective to help other self-learners out there, as Natasha and few others have generously done. I want to pass along few of Natash's invaluable tips that helped me during my first week at Hackbright (quoted, not 100% verbatim):</p>

<ol>
<li>What is your <a href="http://natashatherobot.com/2012/01/23/to-learn-to-code-you-need-to-know-your-learning-style/">learning style</a>?</li>
<li>How can you optimize your resources to benefit your learning style?</li>
<li>Take ownership of your own learning and growth!</li>
</ol>


<p>To conclude, here is my present reply to the above question: Can I become a software engineer? Yes--only if I make it happen.  <br></p>

<p><i>Moon Limb</i><br></p>

<p>P.S. Thank you for reading my first blog post! I promise, there are more technical and programming related posts to come.</p>

<hr />


<p>“Success comes to those that dare to dream dreams and are foolish enough to try and makge them come true.” -- Vinod Khosla (<a href="https://twitter.com/vkhosla">@vkhosla</a>)
g</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
